<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lims on </title>
    <link>https://nara3m.github.io/tag/lims/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lims on </description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;` Marella `{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://nara3m.github.io/tag/lims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrument Log Book</title>
      <link>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/mstracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/mstracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I Created Excel Macro enabled log book for instruments for Mass Spectrometry Facility at CeMM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monthly worksheets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use (example Copy-Paste) and intuitive Excel interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macro enabled color coding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated calendar to grey out weekends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use Excel plotting function for reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple, light-weight and cost effective solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Operations Software</title>
      <link>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/ilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/ilab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;iLab core facility management is a web-based enterprise software solution composed of a base software suite and add-on modules and integrations. The software facilitates service request, customer, and project management, as well as billing and invoicing, among other functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, Mass Spectrometry facility at CeMM was using macro enabled Excel-sheets, postgres database, php/java based web tool to manage core facility operations. The existing set up was hard to maintian becuase of the end-of-life support for backend python, php, java and Scientific Linux OS. Therefore, in the first year of joining CeMM, while keeping the existing infrastructure operational, I deployed, trained staff and maintained iLab Operations Software to streamline information management at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eu.ilabsolutions.com/service_center/show_external/3656&#34;&gt;Molecular Discovery Platform (MDP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_2.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_3.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_4.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_5.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with iLab Software deployment, I brought the following benefits to the Core facility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage requests easily with iLab’s streamlined and straightforward workflow with request management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use and intuitive interface for managing reservations with resource scheduling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View dynamic reports within the system or download the underlying data for business intelligence analysis from the usage, request, and billing data stored in the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and intuitive billing platform ensures accurate accounting and timely compensation with the billing and invoicing module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced customer management tool uses association and filtering options for customized searches and allows the core to easily manage customer details in one place with people search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iLab core facility management software saved time and money for CeMM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
