<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lims on </title>
    <link>https://nara3m.github.io/tag/lims/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lims on </description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;` Marella `{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://nara3m.github.io/tag/lims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Operations Software</title>
      <link>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/ilab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/ilab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;iLab core facility management is a web-based enterprise software solution composed of a base software suite and add-on modules and integrations. The software facilitates service request, customer, and project management, as well as billing and invoicing, among other functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years, Mass Spectrometry facility at CeMM was using macro enabled Excel-sheets, postgres database, php/java based web tool to manage core facility operations. The existing set up was hard to maintian becuase of the end-of-life support for backend python, php, java and Scientific Linux OS. Therefore, in the first year of joining CeMM, while keeping the existing infrastructure operational, I deployed, trained staff and maintained iLab Operations Software to streamline information management at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eu.ilabsolutions.com/service_center/show_external/3656&#34;&gt;Molecular Discovery Platform (MDP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_2.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_3.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_4.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./iLab_5.webp&#34; alt=&#34;webp&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with iLab Software deployment, I brought the following benefits to the Core facility:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage requests easily with iLab’s streamlined and straightforward workflow with request management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to use and intuitive interface for managing reservations with resource scheduling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View dynamic reports within the system or download the underlying data for business intelligence analysis from the usage, request, and billing data stored in the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and intuitive billing platform ensures accurate accounting and timely compensation with the billing and invoicing module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced customer management tool uses association and filtering options for customized searches and allows the core to easily manage customer details in one place with people search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iLab core facility management software saved time and money for CeMM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcode32s0hbhb&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://n3slides.netlify.app/slides/example/&#34; width=&#34;1000&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; allow=&#34;geolocation *; microphone *; camera *; midi *; encrypted-media *&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QCloud 2.0</title>
      <link>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/qcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/qcloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://qcloud.crg.eu&#34;&gt;QCloud&lt;/a&gt; is a client-server architecture based software tool to support proteomics laboratories in daily quality assessment using a user-friendly interface, easy setup, automated data processing and archiving, and unbiased instrument evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QCloud supports the most common targeted and untargeted proteomics workflows, it accepts data formats from different vendors and it enables the annotation of acquired data and reporting incidences. I successfully deployed a complete version of the QCloud system at the Molecular Discovery Platform of CeMM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I beta-tested QCloud 2.0 Software and provided feedback to the developers at CRG Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SimpatiQCo</title>
      <link>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/simpatiqco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nara3m.github.io/project/lims/simpatiqco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ms.imp.ac.at/?action=simpatiqco&#34;&gt;SimpatiQCo&lt;/a&gt; is a software suite running on a local server for a Mass Spectrometry service facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a web interface, SimpatiQCo allows facility staff to upload raw or wiff files stemming from a Thermo mass spectrometer or an ABI Sciex mass spectrometer respectively. The software will then analyse the raw file, extract data (ion injection times, scan times,&amp;hellip;) and will also do a Mascot search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up an in house Mascot-server and later linked a collaborative Mascot-server from &lt;a href=&#34;https://corefacilities.meduniwien.ac.at/en/our-units/proteomics/&#34;&gt;Medical University of Vienna&lt;/a&gt; to work with local SimpatiQCo installation. All data from the raw file and Mascot search results are then stored in a Postgres database, which is accessible through the web interface to view several values and graphs for the current run, but also to view long-term data over a time course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore easy to plot e.g. PSMs vs. retention time, to plot the lock mass deviation over a whole run, or to create a plot viewing the sequence coverage of a certain protein over a long time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up SimpatiQCo software at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eu.ilabsolutions.com/service_center/show_external/3656&#34;&gt;Molecular Discovery Platform (MDP)&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cemm.at&#34;&gt;CeMM&lt;/a&gt; under a Virtual Machine running Windows 10 OS (Education Licence, Version 22H2, OS Build 19045.3693)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./2.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./1.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
