<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://nara3m.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;` Marella `{year}</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://nara3m.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nara3m.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nara3m.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the complex network of interconnected branches of Science pushing the frontiers of human knowledge, I am positioned at the interface of three vertices 1. Biomedicine 2. High-throughput Technology and 3. Informatics. Naturally, my early academic interests span a wide range of thema that are connected to the vertices. Over the years, these generic interests ripened to specific expertise - &lt;strong&gt;Development and Application of Computational Tools to solve Real-World Biomedical challenges&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipk-gatersleben.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Institute for Plant Genetics and Crop Plant Research&lt;/a&gt;, I  addressed two research themes 1. Elucidate transcript, protein and metabolite level changes accompanying &lt;a href=&#34;https://nara3m.github.io/publication/plantphysiology/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;root senescence&lt;/a&gt; and 2. Identify gene expression patterns in &lt;a href=&#34;https://nara3m.github.io/publication/potassium/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nutrient perturbed&lt;/a&gt; crop plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://fz-borstel.de/index.php/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Leibniz Lung Center&lt;/a&gt;, the challenge was to develop advanced computational methods for in-depth interpretation of Mass Spectrometry (MS) data. To this end, 1. I designed, built and implemented a novel metric for determining &lt;a href=&#34;https://nara3m.github.io/publication/ploscompbio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;lipidome homology&lt;/a&gt; and 2. developed an error modeling technique to make MS data driven biological insights robust to instrument threshold perturbations. At the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbs.res.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Center for Biological Sciences&lt;/a&gt;, I applied sequence alignment algorithms for small molecule structure comparison and developed a stochastic model of &lt;a href=&#34;https://nara3m.github.io/post/translation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Transcription&lt;/a&gt;. At the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ccmb.res.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Cellular and Molecular Biology&lt;/a&gt;, the focus was to reconstruct microbial metabolic pathways from publicly available databases and analyze the network topology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Away from work, I enjoy bicyling, running and reading. Favorite book is To Kill a Mocking Bird by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harper_Lee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Harper Lee&lt;/a&gt;. Favorite running event is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polar_Night_Halfmarathon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tromsø Polar Night Halfmarathon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
